Bahar D Viniche

+1 647-213-4474 | bahardv@yorku.ca | linkedin.com/bahardv | github.com/bahardv

SUMMARY

I am a PhD candidate in Transportation Engineering and Management at York University and a researcher in the Interactive-OR Lab. My research is centered around advancing data-driven decision-making in Supply Chain Management and Logistics. I work under the supervision of Mehdi Nourinejad at the Lassonde School of Engineering, York University and Opher Baron and Oded Berman at the Rotman School of Management, University of Toronto. I'm currently focusing on developing sustainable multi-echelon last-mile delivery solutions using novel delivery technologies.

EDUCATION

Phd in Transportation Engineering

Toronto, Canada

York University and Rotman School of Management, University of Toronto

Jan 2021 - Current

Thesis:Design of multi-echelon last-mile delivery systems. Supervisors: Dr. Mehdi Nourinejad, Dr. Opher Baron, Dr. Oded Berman

Courses: Intelligent Transportation System, Information Networks, Transportation Network Modelling

Teaching Assistantships: Capstone Design Project, Civil Engineering Project Management, Pavement Materials and Design

MSc in Air Transportation

Tehran, Iran

Sharif University of Technology

Sep 2016 - Dec 2018

Thesis: Airline Development Model based on Sub-Systems Dependencies. Graduated with Distinction. (Thesis Grade: Excellent)

Courses: Game Theory, System Dynamics, Optimal Design 1&2, Advanced Auto Control, Advanced Mathematics.

Teaching Assistantships: System Dynamics, CAD, Aircraft Performance.

B.S.c in Aerospace Enginering

Tehran, Iran

Sharif University of Technology

Sep 2011 - Dec 2015

Graduated with Distinction (Thesis Grade: Excellent)

Teaching Assistantships: Mechanics of Material.

AWARDS

Women in Transportation Graduate Student Award

Toronto, Canada

2023

WTS (Women in Transportation)-Toronto Area Chapter

Toronto, Canada

Academic Excellent Award York University Faculty of Graduate Studies

2023 & 2022

Ranked 23rd among more than 5,000 participants

Tehran, Iran

2016

Aerospace Engineering Graduate University Entrance Exam

Tehran, Iran

Ranked top 0.1% among more than 400,000 participants

National University Entrance Exam

2011

Publications and Presentations

Journal Publications

Recipient-Dependent Last-Mile Delivery Routing With Autonomous Vehicle Applications.

Bahar D Viniche, Mehdi Nourinejad, Opher Baron, Oded Berman. Reject and Resubmit (submitted) - Transportation Science

Parametric Design of Time-Sensitive Routing With Recipient-Dependent Contributions.

Bahar D Viniche, Mehdi Nourinejad, Opher Baron, Oded Berman. Ready for submission to Transportation Research: Part C

Tactical Fleet Planning in Drone-Enabled Deliveries.

Bahar D Viniche, Mehdi Nourinejad, Opher Baron, Oded Berman. Ready for Submission to Production and Operation Management (POM)

Conference Presentations

Tactical Fleet Planning in Drone Enabled Deliveries and Predicting Drone Delivery Efficiency in Urban Areas using GNNs. Purdue Operations Conference, 2024, West Lafayette, US

Autonomous Vehicle Applications in Recipient-Dependent Deliveries. Canadian Operational Research Society (CORS), 2023, Montreal, Canada

Tactical Fleet Planning in Drone-Enabled Deliveries.

informs Annual Meeting, 2023, Pheonix, US

Fleet Composition Optimization in Drone Enabled Deliveries.

102nd Annual meeting of Transportation Research Board (TRB), 2023, Washington D.C., US

Fleet Composition Optimization in Drone Enabled Deliveries.

Canadian Operational Research Society (CORS), 2022, Vancouver, Canada

Airline Dynamic Modeling for Uniform Development Based on Sub-Systems Dependencies.

Third Annual Workshop on System Dynamics in Transportation Modelling, 2020, Palermo, Italy

EXPERIENCE

Research and Development Engineer

Sepehran Airline (FlySepehran)

· Airline Cost Management Researcher.

Aug 2019 - Jul 2020

Tehran, Iran

Aviation Intern Isfahan International Airport

· Internship in Flight Control Tower.

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014 Isfahan, Iran

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python (Pandas, Gurobi, etc.), Matlab, JavaScript, Wolfram Mathematica.

Soft Skill: Time Management, Engaging Presentation, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation.

SERVICE RECORDS

Graduate Representative in The Learning Curriculum and Students (LCS) Committee Lassonde School of Engineering	Sep 2023 – Jul 2024 Toronto, Canada
Session Chair 2023 informs Annual Meeting	Oct 2023 Pheonix, US
Moderator and Presenter in CLUE Symposium City Logistics and Urban Economics (CLUE)	Jan 2022 – Current Toronto, Canada
Session Chair 2023 Canadian Operation Research Conference (CORS)	Jun 2023 Montreal, Canada
Mentor in the Hack ITE York University ITE York University Student Chapter	Feb 2022 Toronto, Canada
Graduate Representative in Equity, Diversity and Inclusion (EDI) Subcommittee York University	Sep 2021 – Jun 2022 Toronto, Canada
SFC Graduate Research Assistance Smart Freight Center	Jan 2021 – Current Toronto, Canada
Central Council Member of Sharif University Mountaineering Group Sharif University of Technology	Sep 2011 – Aug 2016 Tehran, Iran
Volunteer Tutor at Yarigaran Group to Providing Free Education to underserved students. Sharif University of Technology	Sep 2011 – Aug 2013 Tehran, Iran